TOM CAPERS

615-202-4820 * TOMPCAPERS@GMAIL.COM * LOS ANGELES, CA

PROFILE

Experienced financial services professional and UCLA Coding Boot Camp graduate motivated to build a career in the web development industry. Highly organized, results oriented professional with talent for balancing production needs with customer service and efficiency. Recognized for ability to lead and guide operating units while increasing technical expertise, skills and knowledge of staff. Excels at learning and applying new skills in fast paced and demanding environments. Strong team player that is also able to work independently on projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, HTML, SQL, NoSQL **Applications:** GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Heroku **Tools:** Node, Express, Handlebars, React, Bootstrap

PROJECTS

Syntax-Trainer

- Summary: Typing trainer to practice writing code with proper syntax in various languages
- Role: Database installation, Front and Back End functionality
- Tools: React, Express, JavaScript, MySQL, CSS, Bootstrap

WikisHub

- Summary: Application to discover various wikis with the ability for users to save, share, and submit their favorite wikis from their profile
- Role: Database installation, Front and Back End functionality
- Tools: JavaScript, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, CSS, Boostrap

TechBlog

- Summary: Application for users to read, post, and comment on blogs about technology topics of interest
- Role: Sole author
- Tools: JavaScript, Express, Handlebars, MySQL, CSS, Boostrap

EXPERIENCE

Ares Management, LLC

Senior Associate (January 2018 to February 2020)

- Oversight of day to day activity with the back office administrator to ensure all end of day deliverables have been met
- Managed the daily operations processes in regards to delayed draw and revolver fundings, as well as new deal closing processes
- Ensured all daily wire production was completed and released
- Reviewed credit docs to ensure onboarding of all new deals, loan restructures, and amendments were booked accurately
- Researched and resolved discrepancies related to cash and security data whether transactional or

- analytical in regards to downstream systems
- Liaised between internal ops teams, portfolio managers, traders, and trustees for all security specific activities and issues, ensuring communication of critical information between departments
- Developed, monitored, and reported Key Performance Indicators for management to report on a monthly or adhoc basis
- Maintained customer relationships with the borrowers and lenders and handled escalated customer requests
- Worked with IT to develop and deliver adhoc reports to front office an accounting teams

SS&C Technologies

May 2013 to August 2017

Manager – Agency Services (December 2013 to August 2017)
Senior Associate – Agency Services (August 2013 – December 2013)
Ares Management (May 2013 – August 2013)

- Took over all daily servicing tasks and review function from the client
- · Coordinated daily tasks between team members in Los Angeles, New York, and India
- Trained team members on all tasks including transaction processing, deal closings, credit agreement review, wire production, invoicing, and ad-hoc requests
- Reviewed all outgoing wires and transaction inputs
- Supported staff with all procedural inquiries from borrowers, lenders, and client
- Point of contact for the client for coordination and execution of all new initiatives and special projects
- Coordinated servicing activities with borrowers including billing, contract continuance, and voluntary/mandatory paydowns
- Coordinated revolver and delayed draw term loan borrowings between borrowers and lenders ensuring timely collection and distribution of funds
- Processed transaction activity in Wall Street Office and distributed notices to borrowers and lenders
- Assisted borrowers with attaining Standby or Commercial Letters of Credit, as well as submitting amendment and cancellation requests to the issuing bank
- Prepared and reviewed wires for P&I payments, borrowings, and new deal closings
- Ensured timely collection of payments from borrowers and worked custodian banks to ensure payments were released to lenders
- Reviewed credit agreements for details in regards to pricing and accrual details, payment procedures, voluntary and mandatory prepayments, and borrowing procedures to ensure activities are in compliance
- Maintained First Out/Last Out deal structures ensuring proper payments were made to the lenders per the Agreement Among Lenders
- Coordinated and executed assignment agreements with lenders through ClearPar or paper assignments, along with performing KYC and attaining borrower's consent when necessary
- Supported the client's deal team with new closings, restructures, amendments, and payoffs including producing funding memos and coordination of the release and reception of funds
- Responded to ad-hoc requests for the borrowers, lenders and the client's deal team, accounting, and asset servicing team
- Supported management with deal statistics and transaction volumes for billing purposes files
- Assisted in developing and testing SS&C's wire platform for the agency function

NorthPoint Solutions

May 2010- April 2013

Business Analyst

- Supported the NorthPoint developers with requirements gathering, application testing, and data validation
- Provided client support with user training for applications and troubleshooting
- Worked directly with clients' IT and Operations departments to implement various application solutions ensuring expected outputs and goals were met
- Assisted developers to ensure proper financial data was collected for required outputs

Responsible for the following projects:

NorthPoint Regulatory Platform

- Provided client support in mapping their source data to Form PF attributes, and validated granular client data to aggregated reporting values
- Supported quarterly and annual filers in submitting XML filings to FINRA
- Created user guide documentation for the Form PF application

\$21 Billion Dollar Hedge Fund- Portfolio Reporting Application

Validated holdings, transactions, performance, accounts, and SMF data between production systems (WSO and Portia) and the data warehouse database through SQL queries and worked with the developers to resolve any discrepancies

\$43 Billion Dollar Hedge Fund- Geneva Migration

- Extracted security data from Wall Street Office at the client's site, and position and accounting data from InvestOne at the Fund Administrator, and merged that data into Geneva
- Set up of portfolios, fund legal entities, custodians, calendars, securities, positions for 170 funds
- Reconciled initial trial balances, applied catch up activity with all resulting trades, transactions, and credit activity during the period ending with a final position and trial balance reconciliation

\$428 Billion Dollar Fund Administrator- Bank Debt Module Migration

- Converted bank debt positions that were previously set up as bonds, and converted this information into the Geneva's bank debt module
- Created facility and contract information, loaded credit activity, and reconciled trial balances

Ares Management, LLC, Los Angeles CA

June 2006 - April 2010

Settlements Consultant (March 2009 - April 2010)

Senior Operations Specialist (June 2006 – July 2008)

- Handled all aspects of trading (via Clear Par, TSI or Live Paper) both Par and Distressed Debt
- Confirmed delayed compensation, break fee, and cost of carry calculations
- Communicated with Clear Par and counterparty closers concerning any fee or documentation discrepancies
- Prepared wires and loan documents for closings
- Maintained communication with the trustees and agent banks to resolve outstanding items
- Settled trades and updated contract information in WSO and Geneva
- Performed daily review of loan closing inputs in WSO and Geneva

EDUCATION

- UCLA, Los Angeles CA, Spring 2021 (Full Stack Coding Boot Camp Certificate)
- Tennessee State University, Nashville TN, Spring 2006 (B.A. in Econ/Finance)

Investment Operations Technologies

Portia, Bloomberg POMS, Wall Street Office, Geneva, Clear Par, TSI, SQL Server Management Studio